<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on NoSQL Asia </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://nosqlasia.github.io/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>NoSQL Asia</author>
    
    <updated>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>NoSQL Asia Starts 2015 with a Full House in KL on January 29th</title>
      <link>http://nosqlasia.github.io/blog/nosql-asia-starts-2015-with-a-full-house-in-kl-on-january-29th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>NoSQL Asia</author>
      <guid>http://nosqlasia.github.io/blog/nosql-asia-starts-2015-with-a-full-house-in-kl-on-january-29th/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been over a year since we had our last dedicated NoSQL meet-up, and since they say that the best things in life are worth the wait, it&amp;rsquo;s once again proven true when looking at the line-up we have planned for January the 29th, 2015. &lt;strong&gt;Speaking of which, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to book quickly as we&amp;rsquo;re already nearing peak capacity and haven&amp;rsquo;t even published this blog post yet!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our spectacular speakers and agenda for the evening includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19:00 to 19:45&lt;/strong&gt; - Networking and Pizza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19:45 to 20:00&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/parasquid&#34;&gt;Tristan Gomez&lt;/a&gt; (Mindvalley)&lt;br /&gt;An Introduction / Overview of NoSQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20:00 to 20:30&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mcascallares&#34;&gt;Matias Cascallares&lt;/a&gt; (MongoDB)&lt;br /&gt;Document Schemas and MongoDB Use-Cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20:30 to 21:00&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rickardoberg&#34;&gt;Rickard Oberg&lt;/a&gt; (Neo4j)&lt;br /&gt;Graph Database Use-Cases and Cypher Syntax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21:00 to 21:30&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/chrishampart&#34;&gt;Chris Hampartsoumian&lt;/a&gt; (Amazon)&lt;br /&gt;Introducing DynamoDB and Its Users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nosql-asia-presents-an-evening-with-nosql-tickets-15001711523&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited seating - click here to book your place on  Eventbrite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/starting-2015/nosqlevent.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mindvalley Hall of Awesomeness&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With two international speakers coming-in from Singapore and two that reside here in Kuala Lumpur ready to talk about the technicalities and practical use-cases for NoSQL technology. This will be an awesome opportunity for those that have always relied on MySQL and similar databases for their web projects to see why so many developers are leaning towards different data types such as graphs, key-value stores or JSON documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, this will provide you with the opportunity to hear from people working on the core products they are promoting and give you the chance to network with other like-minded individuals that are using these technologies in production. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good place to grab a slice of pizza after work and hang-out in one of the most awesome meeting spaces in KL and learn more about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.projectrenaissance.com/&#34;&gt;Project Renaissance&lt;/a&gt; movement being managed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindvalley.com&#34;&gt;Mindvalley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed, we&amp;rsquo;ve also re-designed our website. This was originally launched over a year ago and was done with the purpose of trying to organize a two-day NoSQL conference in Kuala Lumpur. We had an overwhelming interest from people all over the world who wanted to present and attend but were never able to raise enough sponsorship interest. The majority of ongoing updates since then have been taking place on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NoSQL KL - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/nosqlkl/&#34;&gt;https://fb.com/groups/nosqlkl/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KL MongoDB User Group - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/klmug/&#34;&gt;https://fb.com/groups/klmug/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big Data Malaysia - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/bigdatamy/&#34;&gt;https://fb.com/groups/bigdatamy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve popped-up here and there over the past year or so whilst helping with Big Data Week and hosting other cross-over events, but the question of long term value with the NoSQL Asia brand was always a question. That is, until recent discussions with the ever-expanding Big Data Malaysia community, where it became clear that there remained an interest and need for the NoSQL Asia group. As a result of that discussion and the possibility for new partnerships in the future, and renewed interest from the community in the possibility of an all day event, a few of us helping with the group decided to refocus our efforts on clarifying the value of the NoSQL Asia brand. For now, we want to ensure that we keep a better record of group activities within the region and content delivered at meetups or curated for relevance. What you see now is a temporary holding pattern whilst we better plan for the future, and look forward to sharing more about this at our up-coming meetup on January the 29th, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss / share the event on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/events/1556753981209665/&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the future. Welcome to 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nosql-asia-presents-an-evening-with-nosql-tickets-15001711523&#34;&gt;BIG Event&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday the 29th of January.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st NoSQL Asia Event in Malaysia</title>
      <link>http://nosqlasia.github.io/blog/1st-nosql-asia-event-in-malaysia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>NoSQL Asia</author>
      <guid>http://nosqlasia.github.io/blog/1st-nosql-asia-event-in-malaysia/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Would firstly like to thank all those that attended and made such a wonderful evening possible. Without you and your interest in life beyond SQL, we would not have been able to launch our community initiative in style. Your thirst for knowledge inspires us to do more! Let&amp;rsquo;s also take this opportunity to thank our generous sponsors (&lt;a href=&#34;http://geomash.com/&#34;&gt;GeoMash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindvalley.com/&#34;&gt;Mindvalley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://acunu.com/&#34;&gt;Acunu&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://planyourwedding.my/&#34;&gt;Plan Your Wedding&lt;/a&gt;), without which, we would not have been able to have such fabulous food, not to mention buy prizes to bribe you into talking to us during the Q&amp;amp;A sessions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/nosql-kl/01/sponsors.png&#34; alt=&#34;sponsors&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;So what went-down on that fateful night where history was made&amp;hellip;?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started the evening by first covering our official mission statement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the mission of NoSQLasia.org to provide free access to NoSQL news, event placement, product announcements and service promotion for individuals, companies and organizations throughout South East Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then gave a &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt; inspired introduction to NoSQL and set the stage for our three domain-specialists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/rickardoberg&#34;&gt;Rickard Oberg&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://neo4j.com/&#34;&gt;Neo4j&lt;/a&gt; Introduced Graphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/parasquid&#34;&gt;Tristan Gomez&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindvalley.com/&#34;&gt;Mindvalley&lt;/a&gt; Introduced Aggregates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/roguejs&#34;&gt;Ruben Tan&lt;/a&gt; Discussed Client-Side Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to entice the audience to participate during the Q&amp;amp;A sessions, we did a little experiment. We told everyone that with each question, we would add their name to a hat, and raffle of a rather swanky prize at the end of the evening. &amp;ldquo;How did that experiment go?&amp;rdquo; You may ask&amp;hellip; Let&amp;rsquo;s just say it&amp;rsquo;s the first time we had to bring the questions to an end in order to get on to the next presentation. The prize was a wifi-enabled 1TB hard-drive with media-playback functionality and was quite resentful when finally handing it over to the winner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also attached a few photos and the presentations below - for more details and comments, please visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/nosqlkl/&#34;&gt;NoSQL KL Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>